<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Reading | bhamburg.github.io]]></title>
  <link href="http://bhamburg.github.io/blog/categories/reading/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://bhamburg.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-12T16:07:18-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://bhamburg.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Brian Hamburg]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 6: Don't Listen to Your Parents]]></title>
    <link href="http://bhamburg.github.io/blog/2014/03/10/day-6-dont-listen-to-your-parents/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-10T21:52:30-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://bhamburg.github.io/blog/2014/03/10/day-6-dont-listen-to-your-parents</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today was a travel day. Andrea has nurse practitioner conference all week in Boston so I took the opportunity to use some vacation time to accompany her and hang out in Beantown. Since I was away from an internet connection, I stayed productive by catching up on my reading and creating a Ruby program from scratch.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m about halfway through <a href="http://www.amazon.com/The-Passionate-Programmer-Remarkable-Development/dp/1934356344"><em>The Passionate Programmer</em></a> and I&rsquo;m finding a ton of insight that I can relate to in this book. One chapter that really stood out was 6: &ldquo;Don&rsquo;t Listen To Your Parents.&rdquo; It&rsquo;s not as disrespectful as it sounds, and by no means is the author (or am I) trying to undermine the authority of parents of potential IT students everywhere. The main point he&rsquo;s trying to make is that the days of taking the safe and secure career path and staying at one job until retirement are over, especially for IT professionals. The following thoughts really hit home, especially regarding some recent conversations.</p>

<blockquote><p>More than any other third party you might look to, your parents are going to give you fear-driven advice. Fear-driven advice is geared toward <em>not losing</em>. Thinking about not losing is <em>not</em> the way to win! Winners take risks. They think about where they want to go&mdash;not where the rest of the pack is.</p></blockquote>

<p>The author goes on to explain this isn&rsquo;t just a rah-rah speech for individuals to follow their pie-in-the-sky dreams. There are logical, pragmatic reasons for a software developer to seek out a variety of experiences that can only come from having developed in multiple environments and having solved a variety of problems. In fact, he calls having only worked at one company a liability and a possible strike against a job candidate. Also, he aruges that truly enjoying one&rsquo;s work is the only way to become excellent and have a remarkable career.</p>

<p>Hear, hear.</p>

<h2>Ruby Practice: <code>99bottles.rb</code></h2>

<p>In an attempt to synthesize some of the concepts I&rsquo;ve learned from <a href="http://rubybits.codeschool.com/">Ruby Bits</a>, I created a program that uses inline <code>if</code> and <code>unless</code> statements to minimize the amount of code necessary to set default values and get the grammar correct for the lyrics to &ldquo;N Bottle(s) Of Beer On The Wall.&rdquo;</p>

<p>```ruby 99bottles.rb</p>

<h1>Get user&rsquo;s favorite beer</h1>

<p>print &ldquo;What is your favorite beer? (default is Sam Adams)\n&rdquo;
beer = gets.chomp.split.map(&amp;:capitalize).join(&lsquo; &rsquo;)
beer = &ldquo;Sam Adams&rdquo; if beer == &ldquo;&rdquo;</p>

<h1>Get user&rsquo;s number of bottles</h1>

<p>print &ldquo;How many bottles of #{beer} do you have? (default is 99)\n&rdquo;
n = gets.to_i
n = 99 if n == 0</p>

<h1>Print lyrics</h1>

<p>while n > 0</p>

<pre><code>s = "s" unless n == 1
puts "#{n} bottle#{s} of #{beer} on the wall.\n#{n} bottle#{s} of #{beer}.\nTake one down, pass it around."
n -= 1
s = "" if n == 1
puts "#{n} bottle#{s} of #{beer} on the wall.\n\n"
</code></pre>

<p>end
```</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 3: Required Reading]]></title>
    <link href="http://bhamburg.github.io/blog/2014/03/07/day-3-required-reading/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-07T13:01:28-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://bhamburg.github.io/blog/2014/03/07/day-3-required-reading</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I started reading <a href="http://www.amazon.com/The-Passionate-Programmer-Remarkable-Development/dp/1934356344"><em>The Passionate Programmer</em></a> by Chad Fowler. I&rsquo;m only a few chapters in after the train rides to and from work, but I can already say that this is a book I should have read years ago. The comparisons he draws between his career as a jazz musician and a software developer certainly hit home.</p>

<p>My favortie advice in the book so far comes from chapter 4 in which the author quotes jazz guitarist Pat Metheny, &ldquo;Always be the worst guy in every band you&rsquo;re in.&rdquo; This is really just a clever way to say, always keep company with those who may make you better. His point is that if you&rsquo;re continuously pushing yourself outside your comfort zone and surrounding yourself with people who are better than you are at a certain skill, you will almost automatically get better. I have found this to be true in my own life experiences.</p>

<p>I also picked up <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Practical-Object-Oriented-Design-Ruby-Addison-Wesley/dp/0321721330"><em>Practical Object-Oriented Design in Ruby</em></a> by Sandi Metz, but I probably won&rsquo;t get to start that until at least next week. For now, I&rsquo;ll stick to the first book and do some online exercises in Git and Ruby.</p>

<h2>Codecademy</h2>

<p>As part of a requirement that I&rsquo;ve placed on myself for this journey to push code to GitHub every day, here is one of the early Ruby tutorials I&rsquo;ve completed on <a href="http://codecademy.com">Codecademy</a>. Variables with user input. Fancy-shmancy, indeed.</p>

<p>```ruby names.rb</p>

<h1>Get user&rsquo;s first name</h1>

<p>print &ldquo;What&rsquo;s your first name? &rdquo;
first_name = gets.chomp
first_name.capitalize!</p>

<h1>Get user&rsquo;s last name</h1>

<p>print &ldquo;What&rsquo;s your last name? &rdquo;
last_name = gets.chomp
last_name.capitalize!</p>

<h1>Get user&rsquo;s city</h1>

<p>print &ldquo;From which city do you hail? &rdquo;
city_name = gets.chomp
city_name.capitalize!</p>

<h1>Get user&rsquo;s state</h1>

<p>print &ldquo;From which state do you hail? &rdquo;
state_name = gets.chomp
state_name.upcase!</p>

<h1>Display results</h1>

<p>puts &ldquo;Your name is #{first_name} #{last_name}, and you&rsquo;re from #{city_name}, #{state_name}!&rdquo;
```</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
